Guide to the Becker-Hull Ezra Cornell and telegraph materials, 1844-1933.
Becker-Hull Ezra Cornell and telegraph materials,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Becker-Hull Ezra Cornell and telegraph materials, 1844-1933.
1-1-262
Charles Henry, Hull, 1864-1936.
0.8 cubic feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Notes, letters, documents, and pamphlets relating to Ezra Cornell and to the telegraph, including letters from Ezra Cornell to Alonzo B. Cornell, the Ithaca Journal, Andrew Dickson White, and T.G. Alvord; letters from Ezra Cornell to J.J. Speed and F.O.J. Smith; letters between Ezra Cornell and William A. Woodward; extracts from Ezra Cornell's private journal; Charles H. Hull's notes on Ezra Cornell; excerpts from letters received by Andrew Dickson White in the first few years of his presidency of Cornell University (1868-1872); a chronology of Ezra Cornell's activities from 1844-1858, compiled by Carl Becker; and pamphlets concerning the telegraph. The journal extracts and most of the letters are in the form of typewritten transcripts. Also included is volume 1 of The Telegrapher, a periodical published by the National Telegraphic Union (incomplete: lacks issues 6 and 10); and a volume of printed depositions in the lawsuit of Samuel F.B. Morse et al. against Francis O.J. Smith.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Charles Henry Hull and Carl Becker were both professors of history at Cornell University. Ezra Cornell played an important role in the development of the telegraph, and later founded Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Notes, letters, documents, and pamphlets relating to Ezra Cornell and to the telegraph, including letters from Ezra Cornell to Alonzo B. Cornell, the Ithaca Journal, Andrew Dickson White, and T.G. Alvord; letters from Ezra Cornell to J.J. Speed and F.O.J. Smith; letters between Ezra Cornell and William A. Woodward; extracts from Ezra Cornell's private journal; Charles H. Hull's notes on Ezra Cornell; excerpts from letters received by Andrew Dickson White in the first few years of his presidency of Cornell University (1868-1872); a chronology of Ezra Cornell's activities from 1844-1858, compiled by Carl Becker; and pamphlets concerning the telegraph. The journal extracts and most of the letters are in the form of typewritten transcripts. Also included is volume 1 of The Telegrapher, a periodical published by the National Telegraphic Union (incomplete: lacks issues 6 and 10); and a volume of printed depositions in the lawsuit of Samuel F.B. Morse et al. against Francis O.J. Smith.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hull, Charles Henry, 1864-1936.; Cornell, Ezra, 1807-1874.; Becker, Carl L. (Carl Lotus), 1873-1945.; Cornell, Alonzo B., 1832-1904.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Alvord, Thomas Gold, 1810-1897.; Speed, John J. (John James); Smith, Francis O. J. (Francis Ormond Jonathan), 1806-1876.; Woodward, William A.; Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1791-1872.; Cornell University.
Subjects:
Telegraph.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Ezra Cornell's speeches, printed, 1863-02-12-1864-03-14; Item number (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ezra Cornell's applications for patents, copies, 1844-1845 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Typescript copies of Ezra Cornell letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Recipients include Alonzo Cornell, Mary Ann Cornell, Eunice Cornell, Ithaca Journal, Jane L. Handy, Andrew D. White, TG Alvond
- Typescript extracts from Ezra Cornell's journal, 1845-1869 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photostat copies of letters, 1844-1854 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes Ezra Cornell, A. Kendall, S. B. Morse, F.O.J. Smith, J.J. Speed Jr. From the Smith papers, Maine Historical Society.
- Charles Hull's notes on Ezra Cornell, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Charles Hull's notes on Ezra Cornell, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Carl Becker's Chronology of Ezra Cornell, 1844-1858, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Charles Hull's correspondence regarding Ezra Cornell material, 1907-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Interview of Otis S. Wood (Ezra Cornell's brother-in-law) by Charles Hull, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Telegraph pamphlets, 1845-1930 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
- Ezra Cornell Telegraph Notice, 1854-06-22 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Tariff of Charges for Ithaca, New York, and Erie telegraph lines, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- William Bartlett manuscript, article, and letter, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Excerpts from letters received by AD White, 1868-1872 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
- Cornell University resolutions before the Board of Trustees, 1868-1874 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Woodward vs. Cornell copies, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Woodward vs. Cornell copies, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
- Woodward vs. Cornell copies, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Woodward vs. Cornell copies, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Woodward vs. Cornell copies, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Woodward vs. Cornell copies, 1870-1873 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Copy of "The Pony Express", 1944-05 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Morse vs. Smith, bound (2 copies), 1852 (Box 1)
- Telegrapher I, 1864-09-26-1865-11-15 (Box 1)